좋은아침
Morning.
아직 옷 다 안입었네?
Aren't you
a little underdressed?
이거 써볼까
Oh, here we go.
- 어울려?
- 완벽해
Is that better?
Perfect.
뉴욕에 사는 특전중 하나는
가벼운 노출이 가능하다는거지
You know, one of the perks
of living in New York City
is the casual exhibitionism.
이웃들이 불평하려나?
Oh, are the neighbors
complaining?
아직, 하지만 네가 온 후부터
쌍안경 판매율이 올라가기 시작했지
Not yet,
but the sale of binoculars
has gone up since you
started coming over.
그래? 그럼 밥먹고 나서
Yeah?
Perhaps after we eat,
창문을 더 어둡게 해야겠어
we can raise
a few window shades.
그래
All right.
모지?
Mozzie?
요즘들어선 간격을 두고
노크하고있어
Oh, lately he's been knocking
in iambic pentameter.
전혀 아닌거같은데
Or not at all.
- 닐
- 요원님이네
Neal!
Peter.
- 아는사람 왔으니 옷입으러 가야겠다
- 응
Really glad I dressed for company.
Yeah.
- 네?
- 잠긴 문?
Yeah?
Locked door?
- 정말 범죄가 많은 도시죠
- 그래. 그렇지
There's a lot of crime in this city.
So I've heard.
이번 건은 좋아할꺼야
You're gonna love this.
뉴욕 주변에 사기꾼이..
There's this con man running
around New York who --
아침 만들었네
You made breakfast.
만들면 안되나요?
Am I not allowed?
두명을 위한 아침이라..
Breakfast for two --
보아하니 날 위해서
만든건 아니겠군
Assuming that second plate
isn't for me.
훌륭하신데요. 요원님 수사능력에
감동이라도 받을까요?
Brilliant. You want to impress me with
any more of your detective skills?
좋아
All right.
(괜히 말했네)
Why did I ask?
베개에 얼마안된
두 머리 자국
Ooh. Two fresh head imprints
on the pillows.
침대끝에 있는
샴페인 얼음통
Champagne ice bucket
at the foot of the bed.
로맨스가 퍼져있군~
Romance is in the air.
- 그건
- 오
That's -- Yeah.
Ooh.
이 수사는
그만하도록 해야겠네
And this detective has decided
to stop detecting.
보자
Let's see.
정부 문제?
Department issue?
음, 그거 제꺼에요
Um, I'm s-- those are mine.
I'm so...
음..
Uh...
닐이 어떻게
사용하는지 알려줬어요
Neal's teaching me
how to pick them.
이건 우리가 오후에 하는
스도쿠 같은 거죠
It's our version of sudoku
in the afternoon.
Yeah.
- 좋은아침이야, 사라
- 좋은 아침이에요
Uh-huh. Morning, Sara.
Good morning.
먼저 의심하시기 전에,
And before you ask,
여기에 서랍이나
칫솔같은건 없어요
I do not have a drawer here
or a toothbrush.
내가 물어봤나?
Did I ask?
아직은 어색한
확실치 않은 단계고
We're in that awkward,
undefined stage
데이트 몇번만에,
정말, 내가 무슨말 하는거죠?
where, yes,
we've been on a few dates,
but, really, what's that mean?
전부 어떤 의미야?
What does it all mean?
우리가 단번에
가까워 졌다는걸 의미하죠
It means we're taking things
one day at a time.
- 바로 그거에요
- 더 많든 적든간에
That's what I said.
More or less.
대부분은 더 많지
Mostly more.
아. 다음 사건이
기다리고있군
Ah.
Our next case awaits.
그럼, 두분이서
좋은시간 보내세요
Mm.
Well, you two have fun.
오, 안돼.
안가도 돼
No, no. Oh, no, no, no, no!
You don't have to --
음.. 안녕
It's...Bye.
안녕
Bye.
잘가게, 사라
Bye, Sara!
Yeah.
- 옷 입어야겠구만
- 네
You should get dressed.
Mm-hmm.
- 밥이나 먹어야겠다
- 네 드세요
I'm gonna eat.
Yeah, please.
- 서둘러
- 둘다 드셔도 되요
Hurry up!
You can have both.
전문적인 위조범, 금고털이범이야
20살 밖에안된 당당한 녀석이지
This guy's a skilled forger,
safe cracker,
lots of panache,
and he's only 20 years old.
닐 카프리의 다음 타자를
보는것 같아
Think we might be looking
at the next Neal Caffrey.
Mm-hmm.
그는 해커잖아요.
전 해킹은 안해요
He's a hacker.
I don't hack.
네 말이 맞아
You're right.
그럼, 새천년의
닐 카프리라고 해두지
A Neal Caffrey
for the new millennia, then.
제가 20살일 땐
잡히지는 않았죠
When I was 20,
I didn't get caught.
그를 쫓아
이 아파트까지 왔습니다
We traced him
to this apartment.
- 안에 그가 있나요?
- 안쪽에 움직임이 있습니다
Is he in there?
There's movement inside.
그래, 보이네
Yeah, I see it.
문을 부수고 들어갈수있게
말해주세요
Please tell me I get to
break down the door.
언제부터 친절하게 물어봤다고..
Why, when you ask so nicely...
FBI
손들어!!
FBI!
Hands in the --
오호. 귀엽네
Oh-ho! Cute.
수갑 채울까요?
You want me to cuff it?
심문하기 위해서 잡아둬야겠어
Yeah, we should hold it
for questioning.
왜 웃어요?
Why are you smiling?
똑똑한 놈이군
He's clever.
문 밖으로 그림자를 남기고
일정한 패턴으로 움직이지 않았지
It casts a shadow on the door
and doesn't move
in a fixed pattern.
우리가 가까이 왔단걸
알고있었군요
He realized we were
sitting on him and bolted.
그렇게 보여
Looks like that.
네 시절 전문가들은
로봇청소기 안썼지?
They didn't have robot vacuums
in your day?
네. 안썼어요
No, they didn't.
둘러봐
Mm.
Look around.
어딘가 탈출구가 있을거야
He's got to have
an escape route somewhere.
즐기시는군요
You're enjoying this.
난 똑똑한놈 추적하는걸 좋아하지
I love tracking the smart ones.
이젠 네가 내편이니
도전이 그립구만
Now that you're on my side,
I miss the challenge.
왜 그러세요.
저 녀석이 한건 가벼운 위조에
Oh, come on, all he's done
are a few mildly impressive
forgeries,
이른바 금고털이범, 로봇청소기가
꽃병에 막힌 꼴이라구요
allegedly cracked a safe,
and stuck a vase on a Roomba.
- 왜 그러세요?
- 아무것도 아니야
What?
Nothing.
요원님.
이거 보셔야겠는데요
Boss,
you need to see this.
무슨 생각 하나?
What do you think?
완전히 랜덤인 사진들?
Completely random arrangement
of photographs?
그래요.
실력좋은 놈일수도 있겠군요
All right...
Maybe he is good.
WHITECOLLAR
S03E06 Scott Free
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
들어와, 모즈
Entrez, Moz.
아
Ah.
너의 영혼을 훔치러 왔지
I've come to steal your soul.
아님 적어도 일부분이라도 말야
Or at least part of it.
난 항상 이 미신이
성가시도록 모순적인것 같아
You know, I've always found
that superstition
annoyingly inconsistent.
그래, 난 사무실 가봐야겠어
Yeah, I got to
get to the office.
잠깐이면 돼
Uh, this will only
take a moment.
우리 보물의 부분적인 목록을
되찾을수 없어 실망이지만
Now, while I am disappointed
we haven't been able
to recover Peter's partial list
of our treasures,
아직 희망은 있어
there is a silver lining.
우리의 탈출을 완벽하게
준비할 시간이 있지
Gives us time to perfectly
prepare for our escape.
음. 여권부터 시작이지?
Mm.
Starting with passports?
우리 가명이
보통 얼마나 가지?
How long do our aliases
usually last?
요원님이 닉 홀든을
두달만에 잡았어
Peter caught on to "Nick Halden"
in two months.
- 스티브는 1년동안 살아남았지
- 치즈~
"Steve" survived for a year.
Say "Gouda."
싫어
No.
우리 자신을 뒤돌아 보지않고,
Imagine not having to
look over our shoulders,
몇달에 한번씩 새생일을
기억하지 않아도 된다고 상상해봐
not having to memorize
a new date of birth
every few months.
네가 어떻게 할지 알아. 모즈
I know where you're going
with this, Moz.
FBI가 절대 확인하지 못할
죽은유아의 출생증명서를 만들거잖아
A permanent identity
that the FBI can never crack
requires the birth certificate
for a dead infant.
난 하지 않을거야
I'm not doing it.
브리 드모~
(brie de meaux : 프랑스 왕실 치즈)
Say "brie de meaux."
그렇게 소름끼치는 방법말고
다른 방법이 있다면?
What if there was a way to do it
that wasn't so...
Horrifying?
어떤 건데?
How's it work?
다른이의 신발에 발을 넣는거야
You'll be stepping
into someone else's shoes,
실제론 존재하지 않았던 신발이지
even though they or their shoes
never existed.
수수께끼야, 모즈?
Riddles, Moz?
닐. 날 믿어
Neal...Trust me.
방법이 있다면..
If there is a way...
하겠어
I'm in.
훌륭해
Excellent.
준비할게
I'll set it up.
용의자의 이름은 스캇 리버스
장거리 범죄여행을 다니고있지
Our suspect's name
is Scott Rivers,
and he's been
on a criminal road trip.
지금까지 사진의 7개 항목과
최근범죄의 연관을 확인하였습니다
So far, we've been able
to link seven of the items
in the photos to recent crimes.
우리는 영장을 가지고 있지만
이 녀석은 항상 위장해있어
We have a warrant
for his arrest,
but our guy
is always in disguises.
추적하기 쉽지 않을꺼야
He won't be easy to track down.
닐, 어떻게 한번도
위장하지 않았어?
Hey, how come
you never used disguises?
미소가 잘 먹혔었죠
The right smile works
just as well,
그리고 콧수염이 똑바른지
걱정하지 않아도 됬었구요
and you don't have to worry that
your mustache is on straight.
이녀석 대저택도 털었네요
Oh, this kid did
the Hartford Mansion job?
Ooh.
그는 부유한자들 것만 훔쳤어
He steals items of incredible
excess from the wealthy --
50만달러 짜리 선글라스
Half-a-million-dollar
sunglasses,
순금으로 된 화장실 청소도구함
a solid-gold
toilet-brush holder --
어떤놈인지 알겠지
You get the idea.
그리고 도둑질 할때마다
이 사인을 남겨놓았지
And every crime he commits,
he leaves
this signature behind.
진짜 기부를 한거에요?
Does he actually
leave a donation?
피해자의 이름으로
매번 다른 자선단체에 했지
In the victims' names,
to a different charity
each time.
그럼, '로빈 후디'가 부자들걸 훔쳐
가난한 사람들에게 기부한거네요
So, Robin Hoodie here
robs from the rich
and gives some to the poor.
- 로빈 후디?
- 전 맘에 듭니다
Robin Hoodie?
I like it.
아닐겁니다.
그녀석을 그렇게 부르지 마세요.
No, you don't.
Don't call him that, please.
그럼 네가
그렇게 부르면 되겠네
Well, you called him that.
몹쓸 농담이었어요
It was a bad joke.
뭘 말하는거야?
What can you tell us about him?
그는 아이에요
He's a kid.
제말은, 반짝이는걸 좋아하고
그걸 훔친다는거죠
I mean, he likes shiny things,
and he steals them.
그녀석은 큰돈을 가진적이 없지만
그런 사람들을 분개한거죠
He never had much money,
but he was around people
who did, and he resents them.
도덕은 있어요
He's got morals.
그 기부카드는 절도를
정당화하기위한 방법이죠
These donation cards are a way
to justify his thefts.
부자들에게 돈을 어떻게
써야하는지 알려주는거죠
He's telling them how
they should spend their money.
그리고 자만심에 차있어요
And he's cocky.
거의 잡을뻔 한걸로는
멈출 수 없죠
Almost getting caught
won't stop him.
더 대담해 진다고?
Will he get bolder?
제가 그랬거든요
That's what I did.
좋아. 닐과 내가 안전가옥에서 나온
기부와 증거물을 더 파볼게
Okay. Neal and I
will dig into the donations
and the evidence
from the safe house.
존스, 다이애나
훔친 물건들이 어디서 왔는지 찾아봐
Jones, Diana, find out where the rest
of those stolen items came from.
이녀석이 다음엔
어디로갈지 알아내자고
Let's try and figure out
where this guy's gonna hit next.
- 안녕, 자기
- 응
Hi, honey!
Hey!
자기가 "앵그리버드"에서
오늘 최고기록 쌓은거 봤어
I, uh, saw you got a high score
on "Angry Birds" today.
- 너 여기있는거 알텐데
- 전 판단하지 않아요
She knows you're here.
Oh, I'm not judging.
누군간 초록돼지를
잡아야했겠죠
Somebody has to stand up
to those green pigs.
오늘 집에서 일한다니 좋네
I'm glad you're working
from home tonight.
어떤 사건이야?
So, what's the case?
젊은 사기꾼이 뉴욕의
부자들 물건을 훔치고있어
Young con man stealing
from New York's wealthy.
오, 젊은 닐이네
Oh, a young Neal?
민감한 문제야?
Touchy subject?
- 그런거같은데
- 아니에요
Apparently.
It's not.
이거야
This is it.
이게 로빈 후디가 기부할 때
사용한 은행계좌야
This is the bank account
Robin Hoodie used
to make the donations.
로빈 후디?
좋은데
Robin Hoodie?
I like it.
어제 기부를 했는데,
절도와는 연관성이없어
He made a donation yesterday,
but it doesn't link up
to a robbery.
아직 훔치지 않았으려나?
Maybe something
that he hasn't stolen yet?
아니에요, 그녀석은 물건을 훔친 후
남기는 카드를 통해 기부하죠
No, he needs to make
the donation to get the card.
The theft has to
come after that.
그럼 조만간 일어날
가능성이 있다는 얘기네
Which means it could be
happening any minute.
음, 이녀석은 확실히
센스있는 기부를 해요
Well, his donations definitely
have a sense of humor.
50만달러의 스카치 한병을 훔쳐
He stole a half-million-dollar
bottle of scotch,
알콜중독 재활센터에 기부했어요
(Betty Ford Clinic)
then donated
to the Betty Ford clinic.
Mm-hmm.
이건 장기(organ)
기증 단체에 기부하네
This one's to
an organ-donation charity.
희귀한 교회 오르간(organ)을
훔치려나봐
Maybe he's stealing
a rare church organ.
말장난이네
Play on words.
장기 기증이라.
무슨 생각이 들어?
Organ donation --
Makes you think of?
운전면허증,
장기 기증자
Driver's license.
Organ donor.
교통국(DMV)을 털려고 하는건가?
He's gonna rob the DMV?
그가 훔친것들에는
실질적인 패턴이 없어요
There's no real pattern
to the things he steals.
다이아몬드로 뒤덥힌 휴대폰부터..
모든것일 수 있어요
It's everything from a
diamond-covered cellphone to --
모터사이클(motorcycle)은 어때?
What about a motorcycle?
병원에서 기증자를
도너사이클(donorcycles)이라 부르잖아
Hospitals call them
"donorcycles."
해볼만한 가치가 있는데요
It's worth a shot.
뉴욕에서 가장 비싼 모터사이클은
누가 가지고 있는지 찾아보자고
Let's find out who owns
the most expensive motorcycle
in New York.
힘내죠
Lock it up.
스튜워트씨. 당신은
절도의 타겟이 되어있습니다
Mr. Stewart,
we suspect
you're about to be
the target of theft.
끔찍한데
That sucks.
진지합니다
We're serious.
최근에 고성능 모터사이클을
구입하셨습니까?
You recently bought
a high-end motorcycle?
- 아니요
- 구입 안했나요?
No.
You didn't?
'컨페더레이트 파이터'를 샀어요.
(confederate : 메이커이름) 알겠어요?
I bought a confederate
fighter, okay?
이걸 모터사이클이라고 부르는건
Calling it a motorcycle is like
calling the Queen of England
영국여왕을 웃긴 억양에
부유한 늙은여성이라고 하는것과 같죠
a rich old lady
with a funny accent.
그래도 모터사이클인데요
But it's still a motorcycle.
이건 역시 거물이죠
Dude, this is so much more.
10만달러를 다리사이에
둬본적이 있나요?
Have you ever had 100 grand
between your legs?
- 사실, 있어요
- 아뇨. 없습니다
Actually, yes, I have.
Don't. Don't.
절도범을 잡기위해
지휘본부를 만드려 합니다
We'd like to set up a command
post here to catch the thief.
그런일은 없을겁니다
Not gonna happen.
내 컨페더레이트 파티가
4시간 후에 열리죠
My confederate party's
in four hours --
For this confederate.
"컨페더레이트"라고
말하는걸 정말 좋아하시는군요
You really like saying
"confederate," don't you?
- 컨페더레이트
- 누가 파티에 대해 알고있죠?
Confederate.
Who knows about the party?
- 모두다요
- 훔치기에 정말 좋은 기회군요
Everybody.
It's the perfect opportunity for the theft.
보안장치가 되어있죠
My security rocks.
여기선 누구라도
아무것도 훔치지 못할겁니다
No one's stealing
anything from here.
그 말 자신 있어요?
You want to make a bet on that?
죽어라 자신있죠.
Hell, yeah.
만달러 정도 되는걸
2분안에 훔칠수있다고 장담하죠
I bet you I can steal
something worth...
10 grand
in the next two minutes.
제가 성공하면 파티에
오도록 해주셔야합니다
If I do, you let us
come to the party.
좋아요. 안될 이유가 없죠
Sure. Why not?
농담아니죠?
Is this a joke?
시간은 가고있어요
이제 시간이..
You're running out of time.
You only have...
1분 남았죠. 알아요
A minute left.
I know.
이건 얼마정도 가치가있을가요?
How much would you say
this is worth?
- 만달러 될까요?
- 최소한 그정도지
10 grand?
Oh, at least.
주시죠
I get it.
다시 돌려줘야 한다는
말은 안했잖아요
You didn't say
I have to give it back.
돌려줘
Give it back.
좋아요.
하셔도 됩니다
Fine.
You can set up here.
내 등뒤에 FBI가 있는거네요?
I got the FBI
at my beck and call?
모두 다 좋아할겁니다
Everybody's gonna love this.
안돼요. 이 모든건
말하면 안됩니다
No, the whole point
of a covert sting
is to not tell people.
그 누구도 알아선 안됩니다
No one can know we're here.
그 정장으로요?
In that suit?
좋아요
Right.
난 이번엔 감시차량에 있어야겠어
I'll be in the surveillance van
for this one.
- 같이 가면 안되나요?
- 안돼
Can I come with you?
No.
- 제발요?
- 안돼
Please?
No.
비밀요원이 위치에 있습니다
Undercovers are in position.
데이비즈 요원은
남측 입구에 있습니다
Agent Davies is
at the south entrance.
웨슬리 요원은..
Agent Westley is...
채드에게 맥주를 주네요
Getting Chad a beer.
뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing?
채드가 맥주 좀 달라고 해서요
Chad told me
to get him a drink.
친구로 위장중이거든요
I'm undercover as his buddy.
채드가 두병이나
마시라고 했어요?
Did he also tell you
to double fist it?
아뇨. 당신더러 긴장좀
풀라고 하던데요
No. He said that you
need to loosen up?
알았어
Come on.
안녕하세요
Hi, there.
채드가 당신이
FBI 요원이라고 하던데요
Chad says you're an FBI agent.
- 이분은 총 무서워해요
- 맞아요
He's scared of guns.
Yeah.
가서 겁좀 줘야겠네
Okay, it's time to put
the fear of God in him.
네
Yeah.
헤이, 채드
Hey, Chad.
우리 위장이 얼마나
오래갈지 모르겠네요, 요원님
I'm not sure how long
our cover's gonna last, Peter.
가능한한 그 젊은 녀석이
누군지 알아내야해
You need to make positive I.D.
on our young thief
as soon as possible.
정신 바짝 차리고 있어
Stay alert.
어떤 위장으로 나타날지
아무도 모르니
Who knows what disguise
he'll be wearing this time?
전 삐뚤어진 콧수염을 찾아보죠
I'll look
for the crooked mustache.
요원님이 로빈 후디를 잡으면
노팅엄의 보안관이되는거네요?
Hey, if you're hunting
Robin Hoodie,
does that make you
the Sheriff of Nottingham?
오, 노팅엄의 보안관은 아닌데
Oh, I'm not the Sheriff
of Nottingham.
그래보여?
Am I?
채드가 당신이
바디샷 한다던데요
Chad says you're
into body shots.
그렇죠
I am.
한눈 팔지마, 카프리
Stay on target,
Caffrey.
오늘밤은 안돼요
But not tonight.
제가 운전하기로 되어있거든요.
미안해요
Designated driver.
Sorry.
스캇일 가능성이 있는
사람을 보고있습니다
I got eyes
on a potential Scott.
왜 그 사람이라고 생각하나?
Why do you think it's him?
후드티를 입고있어요
He's wearing a suit hoodie.
뭔말인지 전혀 모르겠는데
I don't even know what that is.
좋아, 그가 맞는지 확인되면
존스에게 움직이라고 해줘
All right, confirm it's him,
then Jones will move in
for the arrest.
잘 알지도 못하겠고,
별 생각없죠? 그렇죠?
You are in so far
over your head,
and you have no idea, do you?
뭔가 말했나요?
You say something?
아뇨. 그냥 오토바이에
감탄하고 있었어요
No, I was just
admiring this bike.
그래요. 정말 비싸보이죠
Sure does look expensive.
- 12만 달러에요
- 비싸
120 grand.
Damn.
우리 만난적 있나요?
어디선가 본거같은데
Have we met?
Uh, I've seen you somewhere.
- 만약을 대비해야겠어
- 모두 준비태세로
Stand by in case
Caffrey's been made.
Everybody ready to move.
저번 채드의 파티에서
보지않았을까요?
Maybe Chad's party last week?
거기 없었는데
Wasn't there.
오, 놓쳤나보네요
Oh, man, you missed out.
인어가 있었죠
They had mermaids.
말그대로, 여자들이
꼬리만 달고 다녔다는 거에요
I mean, literally, girls
wearing tails and nothing else.
근데 이런 모터사이클을
위한 파티라니
And all he has for this party
is a motorcycle?
불쌍한놈이네
Poor guy.
오, 아니죠
Oh, come on, man.
탄소 섬유, 티타늄 샷시,
1966 CC 엔진이죠
It's a carbon fiber and titanium
chassis, 1966 CC engine.
최고속은 260km인데
Top speed of 260 kilometers
per hour...
속도위반 기준은
넘지 않아요
And not remotely street legal.
이륜차의 명작이죠
It's a work of art
on two wheels.
안녕하세요. 전 섀논입니다
Hi. I'm Shannon.
안녕하세요
Hey.
실례하겠습니다
Excuse me.
- 저 사람 맞아요
- 확실해?
- It's him.
- You're sure?
미녀가 이름을 알려줬는데
자기 이름은 안밝혔어요
Beautiful girl
just gave him her name,
and he didn't give one back.
뭔가 수상쩍은 여자에요
There's something
suspicious about her.
너보다 저사람에게 더 관심있어
하니까 그런건 아니고?
The fact that she seemed
more interested in him than you?
아니에요
Not that.
전적으로 그런건 아니죠
Not entirely that.
방금 마실것에 뭔가 넣었어요
She just put something
in his drink.
- 실례합니다
- 뭡니까!
Excuse me!
Whoa! What the hell?!
미안해요
Sorry.
존스
- Jones!
- Oh, my God!
FBI!
모두 숙여요!
Everybody down!
출구를 봉쇄해.
누구도 못나가게 해
Lock down the exits.
Nobody gets out.
전부다 털어놔
You need to tell us everything.
결국 누가 사주했는지 알아낼꺼니까
We're gonna find
who hired you eventually.
지금 도와주면
합의를 해줄수 있어
But if you help us now,
we can make a deal.
그녀에 대해서
얼마나 아시나요?
What do we know about her?
몇몇 강도, 절도의 용의자야
She's been a suspect
in some heists and robberies.
이젠 살인 미수도 있고
Attempted murder's
a new one, though.
그럼 단순한 약은 아니었겠네요
So I'm guessing
it wasn't splenda
that she sprinkled
in Scott's drink.
Potassium cyanide.
청산가리야
몇분내로 죽었을 수도 있겠네요
He would have been dead
in minutes.
전 반지를 구입하지 않았어요
I didn't buy the ring.
조금 고딕풍이긴 하지만
보석을 절대 거절하진 않죠
It's a little Gothic
for my taste,
but I never refuse jewelry.
좋아, 그럼
Now, let me guess.
그 안에 독약이 들어있는
줄은 몰랐다는 거네
You didn't know
there was poison inside.
웁스
Oops.
저여자가 그사람과
어떻게 연관되어있죠?
How's she connected to him?
여기서 뭔가
나올수도 있을것같아
This might have
something to do with it.
저 여자의 지갑에서 나왔어
Found it in her purse.
스캇이 범행한 장소중 한곳에
보안카메라가 있었어
One of the people Scott robbed
had a security camera.
그는 보지못했지
He didn't see it.
이게바로 제가 위장을
싫어하는 다른 이유죠
That's another reason
I don't like disguises.
너무 편해지니까?
Too easy to get comfortable?
네. 그리고 저여자가 그사람을
어떻게 찾았는지 알수있네요
Mm-hmm. It also explains
how our girl found him.
그들 손으로 처리하려고 했나보군
So, I guess they took measures
into their own hands.
그렇죠
Yeah.
사진감식을 해서
We'll run that photo through,
어떤 물건을 훔쳤는지
알아봐야겠네
see which item he stole
while wearing this wig.
어떻게 생각해?
What do you think of him?
이녀석은 인생이
아직 많이 남아있어요
He's a kid having
the time of his life.
충동적이고, 거만하고, 스스로
어떤일을 저지르는지 모르고있어요
He's impulsive, arrogant,
and has no idea how deeply
in over his head he is.
Okay, fine.
그래요.
나랑 비슷한 녀석이죠
He bears a cursory
resemblance to me.
이녀석을 구제해줄 수
있을거라 생각하나?
Think can we bring him back
from the dark side?
어렵긴하죠
It's hard to do.
널 좀더일찍 잡았더라면
어땠을지 생각했어
I wonder what would've happened
if I'd have caught you earlier.
별 차이는 없었을거에요.
요원님
It wouldn't have made
a difference, Peter.
사기는 흥분되죠
The con is a rush.
중독과 같아요
It's an addiction.
변하기 전까진
최악의 상황까지가죠
And you need to hit rock bottom
before you can change.
언제가 네 최악의 상황이었는데?
When did you hit bottom?
제가 그랬다는 말은 안했어요
I never said I did.
예쁜 뷔스티에네요. 누구꺼에요?
(bustier : 여성용 상의)
Nice bustier.
For you or Christie?
가발 쓴 로빈 후디가 훔친
세개중 하나의 항목이에요
This is one of three items
Robin Hoodie stole
while wearing that wig.
정말 계속 그렇게 부를꺼에요?
Are we really gonna
keep calling him that?
물론.
제임스 본드는 아니잖아
Sure.
It's no "James Bonds."
그래요. 아니죠
No, it's not.
그여자가 강탈한
다이아몬드에요
And these diamonds
are from a heist
our lady killer
was a suspect in.
스캇은 비싼 보석을
그녀석이 훔쳤다고 생각하는거군요
So, Scott thought he stole
an expensive piece of jewelry.
대신에, 그는 범죄증거를 훔쳤어
Instead, he stole
evidence of a crime.
스캇을 죽여 증거를 없애려고 했군요
Kill Scott, and they
eliminate any evidence
that leads back to them.
여기 그림에 있는 사무실은
빌딩사이에서 시야가 가로막히지 않았어
The office in this picture
has an unobstructed view
of midtown from an upper floor.
이 높이와 각도를 확인해서
어디인지 찾아보자고
Let's see if we can figure out
elevation and angles
to see where it is.
- 벌써 찾았습니다
- 멋진데
Done.
Look at you.
사무실은 토마스 칼라일 소유에요
The office belongs
to Thomas Carlisle.
그는 강도짓을 지휘한다는
혐의를 받고있죠
He was suspected
of masterminding the heist.
정말 우연적인데요
What an incredible coincidence.
칼라일이라 들어본적 있어
I've heard
of Mr. Carlisle.
몇번이상 우리 관심의
대상이 된적있지
He has been a person of interest
more than a few times.
가서 얘기해보자
Let's go talk to him.
닐, 스캇에 대한 단서가
나오는지 봐바
Neal, see if you can get
any leads on Scott.
이거 들으면 좋아할꺼야
Oh, you're gonna love this.
The street is abuzz.
떠들썩한 거리에서
누군가 널 찾고있지
Someone is looking for you.
이름은 없어.
그는 아이야
No name.
He's a kid.
말은 말뿐이고
설교는 설교뿐이지
Word is he talks the talk,
so to speak the speak.
- 라임 좀 즐겼어?
- 그래
Did you enjoy that sentence?
Yes, I did.
그가 날 찾으려고
하는거구만
So he's trying to find me.
- 네 일을 더 쉽게 해주지
- 그를 만나보고 싶은데
Makes your job easier.
I want you to get in touch with him.
그럴거야. 하지만 우린
작은 신분 문제가있지
I will. But first, we have
a little identity crisis.
여긴 제 동료..
This is
my associate --
다시 태어날 예정이구만
You are about to be reborn.
이름은 필요하지 않지
Names are not necessary.
모지말로는 당신이 출생증명서없이
영구신분증을 만들수 있다면서요
Mozzie says you can create
permanent identities
without the baby
birth certificates.
신분증 농장
Identity farming.
들어는 봤지만
가설일 뿐일텐데
I've heard of it,
but only as a theory.
어떻게 하는겁니까?
How'd you pull that off?
몇년전에, 난 다수의
출생증명서를 적었었지
Years ago, I began filing for
a number of birth certificates.
그땐, 더 쉬웠어.
의심이 없었지
Back then, it was much easier.
The world was more trusting.
지금은 냉소적인 시대죠, 알렉
We live in cynical times, Alec.
그래, 맞아
Oh, yeah, this is true.
그 신분을 실존하는
것처럼 대해왔지
I treated these identities
as if they were real.
성장하면서,
은행 계좌도 주고
As they grew up,
I gave them bank accounts,
도서관 카드,
소득 신고서도 만들었지
library cards, tax returns.
증거자료를 만들었군요
You created paper trails.
난 '인생' 을 만들었지
I created lives,
내게 발을 들이면,
그 삶을 살았던것처럼 되는거야
one of which
you will now step into
as if you had
lived it all along.
넌 빅터가 될꺼야
You will be Victor.
- 빅터가 될지 모르겠네요. 전..
- 넌 빅터야
I don't know if I'm a Victor. I --
Yes, you are.
의지가 확고하고
고집스럽게 자랐어
Strong-willed,
so stubborn growing up.
그리고 네 나이지
And he's your age.
빅터 머로
Victor Moreau.
네가 계획한거야?
Did you plan this?
아니. 운명일까나?
No. Destiny?
굿바이, 빅터
Goodbye, Victor.
Now you.
이제 너
넌 밥이야
You are now Bob.
난 널 좋아한적이없지
I never liked you.
난 네가 좋아, 밥
I like you, Bob.
일본 조각상,
이탈리안 하프
A Japanese sculpture,
an Italian harp,
보관된 스페인 금화
and framed Spanish doubloons.
테마가 뒤죽박죽이네요
Can't really settle
on a theme, can he?
포인트는 모든게
비싸다는 것이지
I think the point is that
everything is really expensive.
어떻게 보이든지간에 말이야
No matter what it looks like.
요원!
Agents!
몇년전 다이아몬드 강도사건에
관련된건 아니었음 좋겠는데
I hope this isn't about
that diamond heist a year ago,
이미 날
많이 번거롭게 했잖수
because you guys have
hassled me plenty already,
아무것도 못찾았으면서 말이지
and you haven't found anything.
아닙니다.
그냥 선의의 방문입니다
It isn't.
This is a friendly visit.
좋소. 술이나 마시죠
Great.
Let's have a drink.
이름이..?
What's your pleasure, um...
FBI 요원 버크와 베리건입니다
FBI agents Burke and Berrigan.
그리고 술은 괜찮습니다
And, no, thanks.
7x3000로 보강된 티타늄
The 7x3000 reinforced titanium.
아름답군요.
그리고 새거네요
It's a beauty...
And brand-new.
그렇소
It is.
가장 비싼 모델이오
It's the most expensive
model they got.
새 금고를 한
이유라도 있으신가요?
Any reason you need a new safe?
Ahh.
내 위치에 있으면
사람들이 항상 뭔가 훔쳐갈려고 하오
A man in my position,
people try to steal from me
all the time.
그 시도가 보고되었나요?
These attempts get reported?
무슨말인지 알잖소
You know what I mean.
- 제가?
- 그렇소
I do?
Yeah.
도둑들은 열심히 일하기 대신
지름길을 택하죠
Instead of working
their way up like I did,
they try to take shortcuts.
자기것이 아닌 것을
얻기위해 말이오
Want to take what isn't theirs.
최근에 뭔가
도둑맞은게 있나요?
Anyone stolen
from you recently?
그랬으면, 그놈들 후회했을겁니다
If they had, they'd regret it.
왜죠?
How's that?
당신같은 사람이
도둑을 잡아넣을거잖소
'Cause you guys would
arrest them, of course.
물론이죠. 그게 우리가
여기 있는 이유입니다
Of course.
That's why we're here.
이 소년을 알아보시겠나요?
Do you recognize this kid?
아니오. 그가 뭘했소?
I don't.
What did he do?
이녀석은 지름길을 택했죠
He took a shortcut --
자기것이 아닌 것을
훔쳤습니다
Took some things
that weren't his.
부자들이 모아놓은
사치품들을 훔쳐왔죠
He's been robbing wealthy people
in the area who collect...
Items of extravagance.
당신이 딱 들어 맞습니다
You certainly fit the bill.
연락이 왔습니다
One of your guys called.
어디있는지 찾았답니다
They know where he's at.
난 가봐야겠소.
더 도와줄거라도?
I gotta go.
Is there anything else you need?
그에대해 뭔가 보거나
듣게되면 연락 부탁드립니다
Call me if you see him
or hear anything, will you?
물론이오
Of course.
멋진 사람이군요
Lovely guy.
훌륭한 사람이지
He's a peach.
뷔스티에에 훔친 다이아몬드를
박아놓을 만큼 멍청하지
The kind of man
who'd be stupid enough
to put stolen diamonds
on a bustier.
So, that really was
Neal Caffrey at the party?
그럼 파티에서 만난사람이
진짜 닐 카프리였단 말이야?
악명높은 몸이지
In the infamous flesh.
알아봤다니까
I knew I recognized him.
그를 위해서 일해?
So, you work for him?
그와 '함께' 일하지
Work with him.
Kind of like a mentor.
멘토 같은 거야
내게서 모든걸 배웠지
He learned everything from me.
근데 왜 너에대한
이야기는 못들어봤지?
So, then, how come
I've never heard of you?
바로 그거야
Exactly.
오
Oh.
호랑이도 제말하면
온다더니
Ah.
Ah, the man himself.
추적당하고있어
You're being followed.
남서부쪽을 봐바
Look to the southwest.
다른 남서부쪽말야
Your other southwest, Moz.
변명이지만, 난 항상
나침반을 가지고 다닌다고
You know, in my defense,
I always carry a compass.
칼라일이야
시간을 벌어야해
It's Carlisle.
You need to stall him.
구두쇠 맥덕 땡겨봤어?
You ever pull a Scrooge McDuck?
그게뭐야?
W-what's that?
스텝 원
ATM을 해킹한다
Step one --
hack an ATM.
암호를 어떻게 풀려구?
How are you gonna get past
the encrypted lockout?
펌웨어의 보안 결함
취약점을 알고있지
Oh, I exploit an unpatched
security flaw in their firmware,
- 관리자 권한을 얻을수 있지
- 좋은데
which gives me admin access.
Nice.
시험 루프를 돌리면,
짜잔~
Then I put it into a test loop,
and voil?
스텝 투는 뭐야?
What's step two?
네가 도망가는거야
Now you run.
ATM 이 돈을 뱉어내고있어
Hey, that ATM's
spitting out money!
여기 와바요!
Hey, check it out!
이런 세상에! 돈천지야
Holy crap, there's money everywhere!
속도 낮춰
Slow down.
여긴 뉴욕이야
It's New York City.
한번 거리를 두면
천천히가는게 더 찾기힘들어
Once you get some distance,
it's better to blend in.
미안해요. 사람들이 날 죽이려고하면
똑바로 생각을 못해요
Sorry. I don't think clearly when
people are trying to kill me.
사기치고있는거 아니면
절대로 미안하다고 하지마
Never say you're sorry
unless you're running a con.
어쨌든요.
FBI가 여기있나요?
Whatever.
Is the FBI here?
아니
No.
하지만 넌 자수해야돼
But you should
turn yourself in.
당신이 닐 카프린데,
You're Neal Caffrey.
다른 방법이
없다고 말하는거에요?
Are you really telling me
there isn't another way?
들어가
Get in here.
수배된 탈주자를 집에
데리고 온거야
You brought a wanted fugitive
into your home.
- 처음은 아니죠
- 도움안돼
It wouldn't be the first time.
Not helping.
요원님은 저녀석이
여기있는걸 모르지
And Peter doesn't
know he's here.
사라는 여기서 뭐하는거야?
What is she doing here?
닐에게 저녁으로
놀래켜주려고 왔지
I was here to surprise Neal
with dinner.
놀랍네요
Surprise.
요원님은 저녀석이
여기있는걸 '아직' 몰라
Peter doesn't know
he's here yet.
어떻게 할지 고민중이야
I'm still deciding what
I'm gonna do with him.
이제 우리가 책임져야돼, 닐
He's one of our own, Neal.
저녀석을 도와줘야 돼.
규칙의 일부분이지
We have to help him.
It's part of the code.
게다가, 마음에드는 녀석이야
Besides, I kind of like him.
저녀석은 어린시절의..
He reminds me of a young...
- 말하지마
- 나 같아
Don't say it.
...me.
어떻게 생각해?
What do you think?
왜 물어보는거야?
Why are you asking her?
난 저녀석을
도와줘야한다고 생각해
I think you should help him.
아주 멋져요
Brilliant woman.
저녀석을 도와주고
자수하도록 설득해야한다고 생각해
I think you should help him
get out of trouble
and then convince him
to turn himself in.
좋아, 그건 말도안돼
Okay, that's absurd.
인생의 기회를주고
세상으로 나가도록 해줘야지
Give him a chance
to live a life,
make his mark on the world.
저녀석에게 다른길이 있다는걸
보여줄수있는 기회야
This is your chance to show him
there's another way.
음, 난 전혀
롤모델은 아니지
Well, I'm not exactly
a role model.
하지만 흡사한점은 있을거야
You're probably
the closest thing he has.
도움이 필요해요
I need your help.
전 절대 마땅한 대상이
아닌 건 훔치지 않았어요
I never stole from anybody
who didn't deserve it.
누구도 다치게하진 않았어요
Never hurt anyone.
다 이해해줄거라 믿어요
I figured you, of all people,
would understand that.
좋아, 첫번째 부분에
집중해보자
All right, let's focus
on the first part.
칼라일이 너를 어떻게
알아냈는지 확인해보자
We need to figure out how
to get Carlisle off your back.
앉아
Take a seat, kid.
당신과 닐이 데이트한다구요
So,
you and Neal are dating.
음, 좀 복잡해
- Hey.
- Uh, it's complicated.
Hey.
스캇이 밖에 있고
사라와 얘기하는 동안
While Scott's out there
hitting on your lady friend,
밥을 한번 볼까
take a look at Bob.
Mm.
정말 놀라운 작업인데
It's truly amazing work.
그 누구도 우릴
찾을수 없을꺼야, 닐
No one's ever gonna
find us, Neal.
그 목록을 입수하는대로
파라다이스로 떠나는거야
We can be taking off
to paradise
as soon as we get ahold
of that list.
우리가 저녀석 때문에
먼저 잡혀가기 전에 말야
Unless we get arrested
for harboring a fugitive first.
우리탓으로 돌리고
계속 도둑질을 하며 살지도몰라
Or Scott pins this on us
so he can live
to steal another day.
저녀석은 그러지 않을꺼야
Oh, he isn't gonna do that.
좋은 느낌이 느껴져
I sense good in him.
그래, 콰이곤 진?
(Qui-Gon Jinn : 스타워즈 캐릭터)
Do you, Qui-Gon Jinn?
음, 혼란스럽게
좋은 느낌이지만 말야
Well, chaotic good, anyway.
닐, 저녀석은 우리 책임이야
Neal, he's us.
요원님이야
This is Peter.
Oh.
네, 요원님
Hey, Peter.
스캇이 어디갔는지
소식 들은거 없나?
Any word on the street
where Scott might be?
별다른 소식 없어요
No, the streets don't seem to
know where he's disappeared to.
그녀석을 얼른 잡아야해
We need to catch him soon.
스캇을 잡으면, 칼라일도 같이
잡아들일 수 있을거야
We catch Scott,
we might be able to bring
Carlisle down, as well.
소식에 계속 귀기울일게요
I'll keep my ears open.
뭐 중요한 일 하고 있나?
You got something more important
you're working on?
아니요, 요원님.
지금은 좀 산만해서요
No. I'm sorry, Peter.
I'm just distracted right now.
- 사라랑 같이 있어요
- 집에서?
I'm with Sara.
At home?
네
Yeah.
닐
Neal.
네?
Yeah?
둘이 같이 있는건 좋아
I like the two of you together.
좋은 영향을 네게 미치지
She's a good influence on you.
그렇게 생각하세요?
You think so?
그래
Yeah.
그녀에게 나쁜 영향을 미치진 마
Don't be a bad influence
on her.
최선을 다하죠
I'll do my best.
계획은 아직이야?
Figure out a plan yet?
생각 중이야
I'm working on it.
들어봐..
Listen...
이 일에 관련되는거 괜찮아?
Are you sure you want to be
involved with this?
어떻게 되던간에
불법일수 있어
Whatever we end up doing,
it probably won't be legal.
좋아, 그냥같은 '회색영역'에
우연찮게 떨어졌다고 생각해
All right, what I do occasionally
falls in the same gray area.
회색영역만 있는건 아니야
This won't be gray.
나 보기보단 법을
내게 편리하도록 해석해왔어
I have stretched more laws
than I care to admit.
- 그게 내가 좋아하는 점이지
- 그래?
That's what I like about you.
Yeah?
보통은 정당한 사람에게
물건을 회수해주긴하지
I'm usually returning things to
their rightful owner, though.
- 왜?
- 바로 그거야
What?
That's it.
넌 천재야
You're a genius.
들어봐, 아이디어가 떠올랐어
Guys, I got an idea.
옷을 보여줘봐
Show me the glass.
계속 네 엉덩이만
봐줄수는 없어
Hey, we got your Keister
off the hook.
여기 계속 있을 순 없다고
Don't hold out on us now, kid.
저녀석에 대해서 확신해?
Are you still sure about him?
그렇게 많이는 아냐
Not so much.
와우, 음.. 아름답네
Wow, it's, uh...
Beautiful.
정말 편해보여
Looks very comfortable.
칼라일의 금고를 털어서
이걸 얻었었지?
You cracked Carlisle's safe
to get this, right?
네
Yeah.
다시할수 있겠어?
Can you do it again?
금고는 전자키패드가 있어요
Safe has an electronic keypad.
내 블랙박스가 모든걸 하죠
My black box does everything.
그 예술품을 금고밖으로
꺼내는것도 포함인가보군
Including taking the art
out of safe-cracking.
금고는 제가 만든걸로
프로그래밍 되어있죠
The art was programming
this thing,
which I did myself.
널 칼라일의 사무실에
들어갈 수 있게해서
We need to get you
into Carlisle's office
부스티에를 돌려놔야겠어
so you can
put the bustier back.
그다음, 익명의 제보를
요원님께 전달하고
Then we could
anonymously tip Peter
칼라일의 금고에서
다이아몬드 옷이 발견되는거지
that the diamonds could be found
in Carlisle's private safe.
요원님이 움직여 처음에
다이아몬드를 훔친 칼라일을 잡을수있지
Peter moves in,
arrests Carlisle,
who stole the diamonds
in the first place.
증거도 남지 않겠네요
It wouldn't even be
planting evidence.
그저 돌려놓는거지
We'd be returning it.
그럼 넌 전혀 훔치지
않은게 되는거야
Just like you never
stole them at all.
공무원씨가 그렇게
받아들일지 모르겠어
I'm not sure the Suit
will see it that way.
요원님이 절대 알아서는 안돼
No. We should not let
Peter know about this.
문제는 내가
누군지 알고있다는거죠
The problem is, they'll have an eye
out for anyone who looks like me.
아까 말한 회색영역이
얼마나 넓은거야?
How big is that gray area
you were talking about?
아직도 닐의 추적장치를
확인중인가요?
You still checking
Neal's anklet?
꽤 오랫동안
집에있어
He's at home.
Been there a while.
들려보시지 그러세요?
Why don't you drop by?
뭔가 꾸미고 있는것같아
Because he's up to something.
스캇에 대한 걸로요?
Something to do with Scott?
그렇게 생각해.
한번 나둬보려고
I think so.
I'm gonna let it play out.
스캇에게 이끌어줄거라고
생각하는군요
You think
he'll lead you to him.
뭔가 계획을
짜고있는듯한 느낌이들어
I have a feeling he's working
on some kind of plan.
하나의 계획
이상일수도있죠
Maybe more than one.
몇 주전, 암시장에
드가 작품이 나왔어요
Couple weeks ago, a Degas
popped up on the black market.
목록에 있는건가?
On the list?
확실치 않아요.
몇 시간만에 취소됬어요
Not sure. It was pulled
after a couple of hours.
누가 내놓았는지
세부적인건 알수없었죠
No details beyond the artist.
목록에 드가작품이
몇개나 있나요?
But how many new Degases
are there?
D.C. 미술범죄국에서
다녀갔을때와 같은 시간이군
Showed up the same time
D.C. Art Crimes came to visit.
아마 우연이겠지
Probably coincidence.
아마도요
Probably.
이걸 안전한곳으로 옮겨야겠어
I'm gonna move this --
to be safe.
좋아, 칼라일의 사무실에 들어간 후
금고를 털고, 부스티에를 돌려놔야해
All right, we need to get
into Carlisle's office,
hack the safe,
and return the bustier.
모지, 칼라일을 감시해
Mozzie, you will keep an eye
on Carlisle.
철저히 다 감시할게
I'll keep all four on him.
주말엔 빌딩 경비원이
한명밖에 없지
Now, it's the weekend,
so the only people in
the building will be security.
칼라일의 펜트하우스는
보안이 더 철저해질거에요
Security will be increased
in Carlisle's penthouse.
다행이도, 아랫층은 아니지
Luckily, not
on the lower floors.
전화접속 상자는
2층에 있어
The telephone-junction box
is on the second floor.
그리고 여기가
스캇이 갈 장소야
And that is where
we need to get Scott.
저 꼭 아기인형으로 해야되요?
Do I have to be the baby?
- 으흠
- 표준규칙이야. 새로운 사람은 아기지
- Mm-hmm. - Standard rule -- the new man
on the team is the baby.
알람 시스템은..
The alarm system won't be --
최첨단이지만
몇시간만 주세요
It's state-of-the-art,
but give me a couple hours.
시그널을 우회하는 알고리즘을
짤 수 있어요
I can write an algorithm that
can bypass the signal traps.
알람시스템은 문제가
되지 않을거야
The alarm system
won't be a problem.
- 왜요?
- 알람시스템을 끄지 않을테니까
How's that?
Because we're not gonna set it off.
우리 방해물은 경비원과
보안된 문이야
Our obstacles are a guard
and a security door
그 문은
안쪽에서만 열수 있지
that only opens
from the inside.
그동안, 넌 카메라만
피해있으면 돼
All the while, you just
have to avoid the cameras.
보안된 문을 지나고나면
모지의 공기총이 필요해
To get through
the security door,
we'll need Mozzie's air gun.
경고하는데,
쌍둥이 올슨처럼
Oh, be warned --
like an Olsen twin,
꽤 얌전해보이지만
펀치를 날릴수도있지
though she seems demure,
she packs quite a punch.
건물내에선 그걸
펴고 계시면 안됩니다
Hey, you can't have
that open indoors.
알아요. 운이 안좋네요.
안그래도 접으려고했거든요
Oh, I know. It's bad luck.
I've been trying to close it.
- 잘 안되네요
- 나가시죠
The catch is stuck.
Out.
여기서 친구를
만나기로 했어요
I'm supposed to
meet a friend here.
신경안써요.
길에서 만나시죠
I don't care.
Meet him on the street.
그전에 뭔가 듣지 않았어요?
Uh, did you hear
something earlier?
네. 들었어요.
천둥요
I did. Yeah.
Thunder.
스캇이 보안된 문을
지나가면
Once Scott's through
the security door,
사라 차례야
it's Sara's turn.
- 정말? 바비인형?
- 표준 규칙이요
Really? A Barbie?
Standard rule.
표준규칙같은건 없잖아
There are no standard rules.
차라리 이 소금통이
더 좋은거같은데
I would much prefer
to be the salt shaker.
당신의 역할을 고려해봤을때
바비인형이 더 적절해요
Uh, considering
your role in this,
the Barbie is more apropos.
실레합니다.
칼라일씨를 만나러 왔는데요
Excuse me.
I'm here for Mr. Carlisle.
죄송하지만 안계십니다
I'm afraid he's not in.
제대로 이해를
못하시는것 같은데요
Oh, I don't think
you understand.
칼라일씨를 '위해서' 왔다구요
I'm here
for Mr. Carlisle.
사무실로 전화해보겠습니다
I'll have to
call his office.
그러시죠
Mm. Do that.
스캇은 이때쯤이면
전화를 우회해 놨어야해
Scott should have hacked
into the switchboard by then.
그래서 스캇이..
이봐
So, Scott -- hello.
그러지말고. 집중해
Oh.
Come on. Stay with me.
칼라일의 비서가 되는거지
You'll be Carlisle's assistant.
칼라일 사무실입니다
Carlisle's office.
칼라일씨 있나요?
칼라일씨를 찾아온 여성분이..
Is Mr. Carlisle in?
There's a woman here who --
더 일찍 왔어야죠!
기다리고 계십니다
About time!
He's been waiting for her.
얼른 보내도록 하세요
Send her up immediately.
어때보이나요?
How's she look?
비싸보입니다
Expensive.
스캇, 칼라일 사무실의 보안카메라를
녹음화면으로 순환하도록해
Scott, you'll put
the security cameras
in Carlisle's office on a loop,
특히 네가
처음에 놓친부분이지
especially the one you missed
the first time.
사라가 올라가면
들어가게 해줘
Once Sara's up there,
she'll let you in.
위로 눈을 유지해, 로미오
Eyes front and center, Romeo.
네, 부인
Yes, ma'am.
부인이라 부르지마
Don't call me "ma'am."
스캇이 금고의 키패드를 다시 뚫고,
부스티에를 돌려놓고, 집으로 가는거지
Then, Scott hacks
the safe's keypad again,
puts the bustier back,
and we're home free.
같은 금고가 아니에요
This is not the same safe.
못하겠어?
You can't crack this?
구식 금고는
제스타일이 아니에요
Old school's
not really my style.
이런차림으로 금고를 터는건
내스타일은 아니지만
Okay, and mine is not
cracking a safe in my bra,
상황에 적응해야지
but we adapt.
산책하러 나왔어?
경치보려고?
Out for a stroll?
Taking in the sights?
요원님
Peter --
내가 추적장치를 확인했을때
얼마나 놀랄지 상상해봐
Imagine my surprise
when I checked your anklet
칼라일의 사무실
바로 밖이라면 말이야
and found out that you were
right outside Carlisle's office.
- 설명할수 있어요
- 로빈 후디부터 시작하지
I can explain.
Starting with Robin Hoodie.
안에 있나?
Is he in there?
대답하지 않는게
더 좋을것 같아요
I think it's better
if I don't answer that.
- 너한테? 아님 나한테?
- 스캇을 위해서요
Better for you or for me?
For Scott.
계획이 있다구요, 네?
Look, I've got a plan, okay?
계획엔 요원님이 알면안되는
부분도 포함이에요
And part of that plan
is contingent
on you not knowing what it is.
난 노팅엄의 보안관이 아니야
I'm not the Sheriff
of Nottingham.
제가 대화에서 뭐 놓친거있나요?
Did I miss a conversation?
난 나쁜놈은 아니라고
I'm not the bad guy.
하지만 스캇이 이렇게
돌아다니게 할 순 없어
But Scott can't be allowed
to run around like this.
누군가 다치게 할거야
자신부터 시작해서말야
He's gonna get somebody hurt,
starting with himself.
그를 데려왔으면 해
I need to bring him in.
알아요.
한시간만 주세요
I know.
Give me an hour.
그 후엔, 그 스스로 자백할
거라 생각해요
After that, I think I can get
him to turn himself in to you.
- 생각한다고?
- 알아요
You think?
I know.
(여기 도움이 필요해)
가봐야겟어요
Look, I have to go.
바로 여기서
기다릴꺼야
I'll be waiting right here.
다시 돌아올 땐
그녀석이랑 같이 오는게 좋을꺼야
When you come back,
you better have him with you.
감사해요
Thank you.
안녕
Hi.
우산 문제 때문에.
무슨일이야?
Running out of umbrellas.
What's wrong?
칼라일이 금고를 바꿧어
Carlisle updated the safe.
저녀석 진지한거야?
Is he serious?
보아하니 그래
Apparently.
폰으로 들으면 민감도가
10배 증가하죠
I increased the sensitivity of
the mike on the phone 10 times.
청진기를 만들었네
You made a stethoscope happen.
실린더를 치고있는데
안먹혀요
I'm hitting the cylinders.
It's not working.
2개의 가짜문이 달린
6개 실린더의 금고니까
That's because it's a six-cylinder
safe with two false gates.
- 가짜문이요?
- 그래. 금고용 부비트랩 같은거지
False gates?
Yeah, safe-cracking booby traps.
하나를 치면
처음부터 다시해야해
You hit one, you have to
start all over again.
- 내가 좀 볼게
- 네
May I?
Of course.
좋아, 내가 만질테니
All right, I'll go by touch.
넌 소리를 들어
You go by sound.
둘이 꽤 잘어울리는데
You two make quite the pair.
여보세요?
Hello?
아직이에요?
Are you done yet?
작은 문제가 생겼지만
조만간 나갈거야
Uh, we hit a snag,
but we're gonna be out soon.
아님 더 걸릴수도
Or not so soon.
최대한 빨리
문제를 해결하세요
Yeah, well, unsnag
as quickly as possible.
그래. 고마워 모지
Okay.
Thank you, Mozzie.
- 무슨일이야?
- 무슨일이에요?
What is it?
칼라일이 여기로 오고있어
Carlisle is on his way here.
좋아, 계속해
All right, come on.
백업 고마워, 존스
Thanks, Jones.
I appreciate the backup.
서두를 필요는 없어
No need to rush here.
다른 문제가 없..
I'm not expecting any...
지 않네
...trouble.
이거 서둘러야겠는데
On second thought,
go ahead and rush.
좋아,
그게 세번째문이야
All right,
that's the third gate.
칼라일이 어딘가
감시모니터를 나뒀을텐데..
All right, Carlisle's got to
have a security monitor
around here somewhere.
- 문이에요
- 귀 좋은데
That's a gate.
Good ear.
못느꼈어요?
Are you saying
you didn't feel it?
귀 좋다고 했잖아
I'm saying nice ear.
아랫층에 있어
He is downstairs.
아직 문이
두개 더 남았어요
Still two gates to go.
시간이없어
We don't have time.
잠깐, 요원님이 왔어
Wait. Peter's there.
칼라일에세 배지를 꺼내는데
He's flashing his badge
at Carlisle.
FBI가 시간을 벌어줘요?
왜죠?
The fed's buying
us time? Why?
요원님이기 때문이야
Because he's Peter.
저번 만남에서 못한
몇가지 질문이 있습니다
I have a few
follow-up questions
from our meeting the other day.
기다려야 하오?
Can it wait?
아니요. 아니죠
No. It can't.
그래요.
제 사무실로 가시죠
Of course.
Come, we'll go into my office.
여기가 좋을것 같습니다
Down here is fine.
위스키는 윗층에 있소.
가시죠
But the whiskey's upstairs.
I insist.
전 여기가
좋은것 같습니다
And I insist
right here is fine.
버크 요원, 맞죠?
Agent Burke, right?
맞습니다
Right.
제가 체포되지 않은 이상
Unless I'm under arrest,
사무실에서 대답하죠
I'll answer your questions
in my office.
먼저 가시죠
After you.
- 멈춰요
- 좋아. 여기야
Stop.
All right, that's it.
마지막 문이어야해
That should be the last gate.
좋아, 엘리베이터가 오고있어
All right.
Elevator coming up!
한번밖에 시도해볼수 없어
We only have time to try once.
네 차례야, 꼬마
It's your go, kid.
물어보고 싶은게 뭐였죠?
Now, what is it
you wanted to discuss?
다이아몬드 강탈에 대해서
말하고 싶습니다만
I wanted to talk to you
about that diamond heist.
어떤녀석이 물건을
훔치며 돌아다니죠
Thought this was about some kid
running around robbing people.
그랬었죠
It was.
하지만 생각해보면 이 몬스터급 금고가
어떤일을 하는지 궁금하군요
But it got me to thinking
what could possibly be
in this monster safe of yours.
당신은 절대 모르죠
I guess you'll never know.
그렇죠
You're right.
이건 털 수 없으니까요.
그렇죠?
Because it's uncrackable,
right?
- 완벽하죠
- 음
Completely.
Mm.
그럼 이건 우연찮게
열어놓은거겠네요
You must have left it open
by accident, then.
이건 불가능해요
That's impossible.
얘기했던 다이아몬드 처럼
보이는 군요
Those look like the diamonds
I was talking about.
당신을 체포합니다.
칼라일씨
You're under arrest,
Mr. Carlisle.
저건..
저건 내거 아니에요
Those --
those aren't mine.
그럼, 당신의 주장은
사무실에 도둑이 들어와
Oh, you're alleging that a thief
broke into your office
털수없는 금고를 털고
to crack an uncrackable safe
몇천만 달러짜리
다이아몬드를 줬다는 말인가요?
to give you millions
of dollars in diamonds?
손드시죠
Hands in the air.
좋아요
All right.
좋죠. 알았어요
All right. Okay.
아. 제가 당신이라면
그러지 않겠어요
Unh-unh-unh. I wouldn't
do that if I were you.
늦어서 죄송해요
Sorry I'm late.
경치 한번 죽여주네요
Damn, that's a hell of a view.
오, 그리워질껍니다
Oh. You're gonna
miss this one.
조금 덜 경쾌한 옷을
입는걸 좋아하는데
I would like to go put on
something a little less breezy.
- 그래
- 가서 말해봐
Yes.
Go talk to him.
고마워
Thank you.
Yeah.
이제 어떻게할꺼야?
So, what are you gonna do now?
오, 제발요
Oh, come on.
제가 자수할걸로
생각한건 아니죠?
You didn't really think I was
gonna turn myself in, did you?
그랬으면 좋겠다고 생각했어
I was hoping you would.
제 나이쯤에
그런 생각했었나요?
Would you have
when you were my age?
아니. 안했지
No, I wouldn't have.
하지만 이건
나에게 관한게 아니야
But this isn't about me.
피터버크 요원님에 관한거지
Its about Peter Burke.
그는 영리한 사람이야.
넌 절대 모르지
He's the smartest man
I've ever known.
그가 날 잡았으니
너도 잡히게 될꺼야
He caught me,
and he will catch you.
단지 문제는 언제인가지
Only question is when.
그 누구도 그렇진 않아요
Nobody's that good.
그는 그럴수있어. 스캇
He is, Scott.
지금 자수하면
합의를 해줄게
If you turn yourself in now,
he'll make you a deal.
네가 절대 얻을수 없는
최고의 합의야
It's the best deal
you're ever gonna get.
그거 알아?
계속 달려
You know what?
Keep running.
항상 어깨너머로 주의하고
Always looking
over your shoulder,
절대 속도 늦추지 않고, 그 누구와도
인생을 공유하는일 없이말야
never slowing down long enough
to share your life with anyone.
네가 차선책을 선택하면
Because you know
that the second you do,
그때가 잡히게되는 때일테니까
that is when he will catch you.
도와줄수 있게 해줘, 스캇
Let me help you, Scott.
스캇은 어디갔나?
Where's Scott?
스캇에 대한 소식 없어요?
Any sign of Scott?
없어.
완전히 사라졌어
Nothing. He's gone
completely to ground.
제가 망쳤네요
I screwed up.
그래, 그랬지
Yes, you did.
하지만.. 칼라일을
잡는데는 도움이 됬어
But...you helped get Carlisle
off the streets.
좋은 승리지
That's a good win.
정말 그녀석을 설득시킬수
있을거라 생각했어요
I actually thought
I was getting through to him.
실망했구나, 그렇지?
Disappointing, isn't it?
음
Mm.
사람들은 말을 들어도
네가 말한 반대로 행동하지
You think they're listening,
and then they go off and do
the opposite of what you say.
이제 그녀석은
어디든지 가있겠네요
Now he could be anywhere.
정말 그랬지
He really could.
하지만 저녀석은 아니었어
But he's not.
그는 닐에게만
자수하겠다고 합니다
He said he'd only
turn himself in to you.
그래서..
So...
이사람이 당신을
잡은 사람이에요?
This is the guy who caught you?
믿거나 말거나, 맞아
Believe it or not, yeah.
여기오다니 반갑네
Glad you're here.
네가 훔친 작품들은
아직 가지고 있지?
You still have
the pieces you stole?
어떤 작품을 알고있냐에 따랐죠
Depends. Which pieces
do you know about?
오. 흠
Oh. Hmm.
협조를 더 해주면
더 좋은 협상을 해주지
The more you cooperate,
the better deal I can get you.
그럼 조금만
형을 살아도 될꺼야
You're gonna have to
serve some time.
알아요
I know.
- 제가 따로 얘기좀..
- 그래
Can I, um...
Yeah.
그래서, 어떤점이 널
자수하도록 만들었어?
So, what made you
decide to come in?
부자들에게서 빌어먹을 것들을
훔치는게 벌써 따분해졌거든요
Because stealing stupid things
from rich people
was already getting boring.
또는 당신이 내게
말해준것 때문일지도요
Or because what you said
got to me.
당신의 기분을 더
좋게 하는걸로 생각해요
Whichever makes you
feel better.
도와줘서 고마워요
Thanks for the help.
언제든지
Anytime.
존스
다시 수갑 채워주겠어?
Jones, could you
cuff him again?
아주 멋진데
Real cute.
다시해보자
Let's try it again.
녀석에게 시간을 좀 주세요
Give him some time.
사람은 하룻밤에 바뀌진 않아요
People don't change overnight.
날 믿어. 알아
Believe me, I know.
그걸 증명하려고 살아가지
I work with living proof of it.
하지만 바뀌더라고
But they do change.
요원님은 노팅엄의 보안관은 아니네요
You're not the Sheriff
of Nottingham.
알아
I know.
'사자심장 리처드'에
더 가깝다고 생각해
I'm thinking more
King Richard the Lionheart.
- 그러세요
- 좋아
I'll go with that.
Good.
빅터 머로
Victor Moreau.
빅
Vic.
빅 머로
Vic Moreau.
머로.
빅터 머로
Moreau.
Victor Moreau.
반가워
Nice to meet you.
잠시만
Just a second.
놀랐어?
Surprised?
다행이도
Happily.
뭔가 하고있는 도중에
들어온것 같네
It looks like I caught you
mid-something.
샤워하러 가려는 중이었어
I was just about
to take a shower.
오
Oh.
그거 진술이야 아님 초대야?
Is that a statement
or an invitation?
그래, 그래
Yes. Yes.
- 조금 있다봐
- 응
I'll meet you in a sec.
All right.
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
영어자막 : www.addic7ed.com (honeybunny)
한글자막 : EzLoves (vstu77.blog.me)
오타, 오역 등 피드백 남겨주세요!